# **ODUOR TONNY BLAIR**

P.O BOX 342-01000 · +254726720085,

Email; oduortonny10@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

I am an accomplished ICT professional with three years of experience, demonstrating proficiency in diverse aspects of information technology. My expertise encompasses software development, Graphics design, Intranet administration support, cybersecurity, cloud computing proficiency, ICT project management, Help desk support Specialist, ICT infrastructure expertise, hardware support specialist, System Maintenance with Technical Support, and database administration. I actively seek opportunities to apply my skills and knowledge in a dynamic and challenging IT environment.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SEPT 2023 - PRESENT

ICT INSTRUCTOR, ANGAZA CENTER NGO.

My responsibilities in partnership with schools;

- Identifying the specific Digital Literacy training needs of individuals and organizations.
- Creating and developing instructional training materials and aids, including handbooks, visual materials, online tutorials, and reference documents.
- Designing, coordinating, and delivering training and development programs, including individual and group instruction, workshops, demonstrations, and conferences.
- Continuously assessing and evaluating the quality and effectiveness of training programs, adjusting objectives, methods, and course content as needed.
- Creating user-friendly training materials such as manuals, online help resources, and operating instructions.
- Conducting research to stay up-to-date with the latest technology trends, software updates, and IT advancements
- Guiding students to come up with projects in areas such as web applications, data science projects, mobile application projects, and robotics.
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting.
- Computer and ICT Equipment Maintenance Expertise.

#### **JUNE 2022 – JUNE 2023**

### IT ASSISTANT, MACHEO CHILDRENS NGO

## My responsibilities;

- User Account Management and Access Control
- Graphics design(adobe suite).
- Serve as a Database Administrator
- Intranet Administration and support
- Computer and ICT Equipment Maintenance Expertise.
- User Account Management and Access Control
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting
- Data Visualization and Reporting Expertise with Power BI, Advanced Excel, and Anaconda Python:
- Software Development and Maintenance
- Cybersecurity and Information Protection
- ICT Project Management

#### **SEPT 2021 – MARCH 2022**

# INTERNSHIP AS IT ASSISTANT, MACHEO CHILDRENS NGO.

My responsibilities were;

- Network Administration
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting:
- Graphics design.

#### JAN 2018 – APRIL 2018

# VOLUNTEER AS COMPUTER TRAINEE, AHERO MULTIPURPOSE DEVELOPMENT TRAINING INSTITUTE.

- G-Suit applications: Google workspace services for communication, document creation, scheduling in cloud-based plus domain management and email systems.
- Microsoft office suite.

#### **EDUCATION**

MAY 2018 - JULY 2022.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION AND TECHNOLOGY,

MOUNT KENYA UNIVERSITY

2014-2017

KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION.

RAMBA HIGH SCHOOL

#### **SKILLS**

- Graphic Design: Proficient in Adobe Suites for creating visually appealing graphics, editing videos and photos, and skilled in Canva and figma for designing various visual assets. Experienced in crafting intuitive user interfaces and engaging user experiences in UI/UX design, and skilled in HTML/CSS for structuring UI. Created a sample newsletter showcasing graphic design skills: <a href="https://ictprogramnewsletter.netlify.app">https://ictprogramnewsletter.netlify.app</a>.
- Full Stack Developer: Expertise in programming languages such as php, dart and JavaScript with familiarity with framework like ReactJS, ExpressJS, laravel, NodeJs for Rest APIs (MERN Stack Developer) and flutter for UI mobile applications.
- CompTIA Certified Network+ Associate with two years of experience in Intranet administration, Efficient at deploying and managing LAN/WAN networking infrastructure and performing troubleshooting activities.
- Proficient in System Maintenance and offering Technical Support.
- Database Administrator, proficient in utilizing relational database management software packages such as Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL and NoSql(MongoDB and firebase).
- Computer Hardware and Software Maintenance: Proficient in hardware troubleshooting, software installation, and system maintenance for Windows and Linux platforms.
- Experienced in providing specialized support for software applications and offering Helpdesk Administration assistance. Possessing expertise in Web Technologies and System Analysis.
- Data Analysis: Skilled in data analysis using tools such as MS Excel, Anaconda(Python) for data sorting, Power BI for data visualization, MS SQL Server for crafting intricate SQL queries, developing stored procedures, and executing data migration tasks, and MSSQL for creating and managing databases, designing diverse database components.
- Version Control: Proficient in using version control systems such as Git, SVN (Subversion), or Mercurial. Experienced in managing repositories, branching, merging, and resolving conflicts. Familiar with collaborative workflows and code review processes.
- Leverage cloud-based platforms like AWS (Amazon Web Services).
- JamStack platforms (Vercel, render and Netlify).
- G-Suit applications: Google services for communication in cloud-based plus domain Management and email systems is SharePoint Online.

#### **FUNCTIONAL SKILLS**

- Goal Oriented.
- Hardworking, self-driven and ready to learn.
- Quick learner who can withstand stress and get along with Colleagues well.
- Creative, decisive, result oriented person and team player.
- Able to work under tight and short strict deadlines.
- High personal integrity and able tolerate with all.
- Ambitious, innovative and analytical with good interpersonal relation.
- Able to work under minimal and no supervision,
- Good listener.
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills.

#### PROFFESIONAL PROFILES.

GitHub: My GitHub profile is a platform where I actively contribute to open-source projects, collaborate with other developers, and showcase my coding skills and projects. It serves as a portfolio of my programming projects and allows potential employers or collaborators to assess my coding proficiency.

- LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonny-blair-893a0520b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonny-blair-893a0520b/</a>
- GitHub Profile: https://github.com/blair-developer
- Portfolio profile: <a href="https://tonnyblair-portfolio.netlify.app/">https://tonnyblair-portfolio.netlify.app/</a>

#### CERTIFICATION AND TRAINING.

- CompTIA Network+ certification.
- Google Associate Android Developer (AAD) by Google Developer Student Club.
- System Administration Certification by Microsoft and LinkedIn.
- Data Protection Policy Training by Macheo Children's NGO.

# **REFEREES**

Mr. Ibrahim Hassan, Coordinator,FHN(Programs), Monitoring and Evaluation. Macheo childrens NGO, <u>ibrahimhassankina@gmail.com</u>,

Cell: 0720581278.

Mrs. Harriet Tsinale,
Lecturer, Computing and Informatics,
Tharaka University,
tsinale@yahoo.com,

Cell: 0725218728

Mr.Afubwa Musumi Director Career and Alumni services, Mount Kenya University

Cell: 0720178684